

Mechanical Engineer & Developer JOSUE BANEGA

I'm mechanical engineer with solid programming skills. I have four years of experience in the mining sector performing engineering analysis and product design using CAD/CAE tools and FEA/CFD simulations. I'm passionate about technologies and app development. I'm always learning about new ways to use the tech to solve problems and make the life easier.

Contact

- engineer@jbanega.com jban3ga@gmail.com josue.samuel.21@gmail.com
- Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela
- **** 0424-9713321
- http://jbanega.co/
- inkedin.com/in/jbanega
- github.com/jbanega

Technologies

- Programming and data analysis: Python and MATLAB.
- 3D Modeling & Drawing: Autodesk Inventor and Solidworks.
- FEA and CFD Simulation: ANSYS, COMSOL Multiphysics and OpenFOAM.
- Web and App Development: HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

_

- Adaptability.
- Problem-solving.

Soft skills

- Creativity.
- Teamwork.
- Self-motivated.

Work experience

Jan 2019 – Jan 2021

LUFH CONVEYOR BELT SYSTEMS

Technical Department / Development & Application Engineer

- In charge of technical drawing and design of 3D components using CAD software as Autodesk Inventor, ANSYS and COMSOL Multiphysics.
- Develop engineering analysis tools with user interface to automate tasks and provide guidance to internal/ external customers. Technologies used: Excel, VBA and Python.
- Write analyses and prepare presentations about the results and work performed. Tools used: Microsoft Office (Work, PowerPoint and Excel).

Aug 2017 – Dic 2018

CVG VENALUM

Technology and Development Department / Technology & Development Engineer Level I

- Perform hands-on concept development and prototyping to improve mechanical system using Autodesk Inventor, ANSYS and MATLAB.
- Running simulation based on finite element analyses (FEA) and computational fluid dynamic (CFD).
- Records and analyses data to reach design/ business decisions in plant.
- Interact with the experimental teams to develop and test new/ existing designs.

Education

2018 – 2019

MODELING AND SIMULATION SPECIALIZATION IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnica Antonio José de Sucre (UNEXPO)

Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela

2011 – 2016

BACHELOR DEGREE IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (SUMMA CUM LAUDE MENTION)

Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB)

Sartenejas, Venezuela

2002 - 2010

HIGH SCHOOL DEGREE IN SCIENCE

Unidad Educativa Colegio Los Próceres

Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela

Papers & Conferences

[1] Banega, J.; Moreno, N. (2018) <u>Aerodynamic Design of a VAWT suitable to wind profiles of Paraguaná by CFD</u>, Revista De La Facultad De Ingeniería, Universidad Central De Venezuela, 31(4), 83-92.

*Presented in The XIII International Congress of Numerical Methods in Engineering and Applied Sciences (CIMENICS 2016), Caracas, Venezuela, 11-13 July.

- engineer@jbanega.com jban3ga@gmail.com josue.samuel.21@gmail.com
- http://jbanega.co/
- n (jbanega

Mechanical Engineer & Developer **JOSUE BANEGA**

Profile

Birth date: 26 June 1993. Nationality: Venezuela.

Teaching & Tutoring

[1] PhD. Caraballo, S.; Banega, J. (Dic 2018 – Jan 2019). Thermo-fluid-dynamic Simulation with COMSOL Multiphysics. Short course dictated as part of MODELING AND SIMULATION SPECIALIZATION IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING VII Promotion.

> Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnica Antonio José de Sucre (UNEXPO) Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela

[2] Bouzas, A. [Author]; Banega, J. [Industrial Tutor]; Andrade, J. [Academic Tutor] (2018) Modeling and Control of a Demolition Equipment to Clean Aluminium Melting Pots. Industrial training in CVG Venalum's Reduction Technology Division.

> Universidad Nacional Experimental Politécnica Antonio José de Sucre (UNEXPO) Barquisimeto, Venezuela

Languages

- Spanish: Advanced (Native).
- English: Intermedium -
- Advanced (B2).
- French: Basic (A1).

Interests

- Python programming.
- App development.
- Machine learning.
- Computational mechanics (FEM/CFD).
- Vibration analysis.

- Reading.
- Travelling.
- 3D Modeling.

Hobbies

- Cinema.
- Airplane crafting.

Certifications & Complementary courses

Jan 2021 GUI Development with Python and Tkinter

Udemy / Online

Jan 2021 Computational Thinking with Python

Platzi / Online

English for Developers Course Aug 2020

Platzi / Online

Jul 2020 Basic Python Course

Platzi / Online

Mar 2020 Fundamentals in Polymer Processing

Instituto de Capacitación e Investigación del Plástico y del Caucho (ICIPC)

Barranquilla, Colombia

Feb 2020 - Sep 2020 Certificate of Proficiency English Level B2

Open English / Online

Oct 2019 - Nov 2019 **Design Thinking**

Instituto de Estudios Superiores de Administración (IESA) / Online

Nov 2017 Temperature Control with Fuzzy Logic

CVG Venalum / Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela

ANSYS CFX - Introduction to V15.0 Sep 2015

ALBATROS Ingeniería & Construcción C.A. / Caracas, Venezuela

Jan 2011 - Jun 2011 French Foundation Course

Lycée Saint Charles & American Field Service (AFS) / Marseille, France

Recognitions & Achievements

Oct 2016 Best Student Award, 2016 Edition

Decanato de Estudios Profesionales de la Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB)

*Recognition by excellent academic performance.